I'm here with Nija, a dev ops engineer here at Udacity.
إنني هنا مع نيجا، مهندس تطوير الخيارات هنا في Udacity.
So tell me,
أخبروني،
how do you consume documentation as part of an engineering team?
كيف تقومون باستهلاك التوثيق كجزء من فريق هندسي؟
>> We consume documentation every day because we use third party libraries and
إنكم تستهلكون التوثيق يوميًا بسبب أننا نستخدم مكتبات وأدوات من طرف
tools.
خارجي.
So, one of the easiest things to do is when we want to get up and
وبالتالي فإن واحدًا من أسهل الأشياء لتقوم به هو عندما نرغب في النهوض
running, we look for an example for how to do that in the documentation.
والجري، سنبحث عن مثالًا عن كيفية القيام بذلك في التوثيق.
>> And what would you do if you did not have this documentation available?
وماذا تود أن تفعل إذا لم يكون هذا التوثيق متاحًا؟
>> We would be very sad.
سنكون حزينين جدًا.
Realistically, we may not use that library, or
في الواقع، من المحتمل ألا نستخدم تلك المكتبة
we may switch to a library that is better documented.
أو يُحتمل الانتقال إلى مكتبة أخرى موثقة بشكل أفضل.
Or we might write our own internal documentation if that's
أو يُحتمل أن نكتب توثيقنا الداخلي إذا كانت المكتبة
really the library that we need to use.
الفعلية التي نحتاج أن نستخدمها.
>> How would you figure out the code if the documentation wasn't there?
كيف تود اكتشاف الكود إذا لم يكن التوثيق موجودًا؟
>> You'd have to dig through the source code a lot of the times,
سيكون عليك التعمق بحثا في كود المصدر عدة مرات،
or examine it using a debugger.
أو فحصه باستخدام المصحح.
Or, a number of other more advanced trouble-shooting tools.
أو، عددًا من أدوات تحري الخلل الأكثر تقدمًا.
>> That sounds like a big headache.
يبدو هذا مزعجًا جدًا.
>> It's kind of like reverse engineering somebody else's thought process.
إن هذا نوع من الهندسة العكسية التي اعتقد شخص آخر أن يقوم بمعالجتها.
Sometimes it doesn't work so well in practice.
أحيانًا لا يعمل بشكل جيد في التدريب.
>> Thanks Nija.
شكرًا لك دايجا.